whitespark.ca 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy Update - Whitespark

We love our customers, and their privacy is extremely important to us.

## In a nutshell

  * We don’t require any personal information that we don’t actually need.
  * We only keep your personal information for as long as we need it (ie. as long as you have an active account/subscription).
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * We don’t store credit card information on our servers.
  * You may opt-out of collection, or request the removal of your personal information from our systems.
  * You may request a copy of all your personal information we have stored.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Whitespark collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Whitespark’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Whitespark’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Whitespark may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Whitespark also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on our blog. Whitespark only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Whitespark’s websites choose to interact with Whitespark in ways that require Whitespark to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Whitespark gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a Whitespark account to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Whitespark – by purchasing a Subscription or Service – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Whitespark collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Whitespark. Whitespark does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Whitespark may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Whitespark may monitor the most popular posts on our blog or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. Whitespark may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Whitespark does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Whitespark discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Whitespark’s behalf or to provide services available at Whitespark’s website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Whitespark’s website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Whitespark will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Whitespark discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Whitespark believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Whitespark, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the Whitespark website and have supplied your email address, Whitespark may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Whitespark and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Whitespark takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Opting Out

You can ask us to stop sending emails at any time or by following the unsubscribe links in any email message sent to you, or by contacting us.

### Retention

We will keep your personal data only as long as needed to fulfill the purposes we collected it for. We may keep basic information such as contact and billing information in order to make it easier for customers to make new or repeat orders.

### Your rights

You have various rights in relation to your personal data:

  * You may request access to your personal data.
  * You may request corrections of your personal data.
  * You may request deletion of your personal data.
  * You may decline the processing of your personal data.
  * You may request restrictions related to processing of your personal data.
  * You may request transfer of your personal data.
  * You have the right to withdraw consent.

There is no fee to access your personal data, or to exercise any of the other rights listed above. However we may charge a fee if the request is obviously unfounded or excessive. We reserve the right to refuse the request in those cases.

We will try to respond to all legitimate requests within 30 days. It may take us longer if your request is complex or you have made a number of requests. In that case, we will contact you and notify you of updates.

### Data Storage & Security

All data is stored in world-class [Digital Ocean](https://www.digitalocean.com/) datacentres, covered by 24/7/365 physical security personnel, CCTV cameras and redundant backup generators. Whitespark uses only secure state-of-the-art encrypted communication with this server network to ensure that your data remains private.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Whitespark uses cookies to help Whitespark identify and track visitors, their usage of Whitespark website, and their website access preferences. Whitespark visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Whitespark’s website, with the drawback that certain features of Whitespark’s website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If Whitespark, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Whitespark goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Whitespark may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Whitespark and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Whitespark may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Whitespark’s sole discretion. Whitespark encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
